NKOSINATHI NGELE

Midrand, Gauteng, South Africa · 0736954921 nkosinathi@nathingele.com · linkedin.com/in/nkosinathi-ngele-074909128 · nathingele.com

Experienced Junior Software Developer with a demonstrated history of more than 2 years working in the information technology and services industry. Skilled in C#, JavaScript, SQL, HTML, CSS and Figma. Strong engineering professional with a National Diploma focused in Software Development from the Tshwane University of Technology.

EXPERIENCE

SEPTEMBER 2018 – FEBRUARY 2019 INTERN, A-SOLUTION

- Developed a Java system
- Developed PHP system
- System design
- Database Design
- Used SQL and PI/SQL for database manipulations
- Writing reports

MARCH 2019 - FEBRUARY 2020

JUNIOR SOFTWARE DEVELOPER, IT MONKEY

- Extracting Transforming and Loading Data using the Talend (ETL) tool monthly
- Generating graphs monthly
- Writing and maintaining .net and SQL code
- Responding to system users' queries with friendliness and expertise

MARCH 2020 - AUGUST 2021

JUNIOR SOFTWARE DEVELOPER, DIGITAL UNBOUNDED

- Frontend design
- Developed and maintained web applications
- Writing and maintaining .net and JavaScript code
- Working on minor bug fixes
- Running ETL tool monthly
- Writing and maintaining SQL code
- Responding to system users' queries

EDUCATION

JAN 2016 - NOV 2018

NATIONAL DIPLOMA IN SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT, TSHWANE UNIVERSITY OF

TECHNOLOGY

I developed both theoretical and practical foundation in various core areas of the ICT (Information and Communication Technology) including software development, database design, Networking (with Linux) and project management. During the course I developed multiple applications using C++ (OOP) and SQL.

JULY 2018 - JUNE 2019

LEARNERSHIP, DYNAMIC DNA

I developed web pages and small C# systems.

JULY 2019 - CURRENY

B-TECH IN SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT, TSHWANE UNIVERSITY OF TECHNOLOGY

I earned more knowledge and skills by learning new things including UX/UI design, database administration, research and real world applications using Java JSP and Python.

SKILLS

- Hard Work
- Ability to learn
- Attention to detail
- Analytical and Solving skills
- Time management
- Team Player

- C#
- JavaScript
- HTML5
- CSS
- SQL
- Figma UX/UI
- Java
- C++
- PHP